Finding aid to the Laurenus Clark Seelye papers CA.MS.00001
Smith College Archives
- SERIES IV. PUBLICATIONS, 1859-1925; 0.83 linear feet
  - "Antiquity of Celtic Literature" (manuscript), 1870 (Box 295, Folder 2)
  - "The Ancient Fenians", 1871 (Box 295, Folder 3)
  - Commission on the Investigation of Agricultural Education, 1918 (Box 295, Folder 4)
  - Early History of Smith College (Box 296)
    - Reviews and dust jacket, 1923 (Box 295, Folder 5)
    - Notes, 1871 - 1910 (Box 295, Folder 6)
  - Drafts (c., 1922-23)
    - Chapter I, undated (Box 295, Folder 7)
    - Chapter I, undated (Box 295, Folder 8)
    - Chapter II, undated (Box 295, Folder 9)
    - Chapter III, undated (Box 295, Folder 10)
    - Chapter IV, undated (Box 295, Folder 11)
    - Chapter IV, undated (Box 295, Folder 12)
    - Chapter V, undated (Box 295, Folder 13)
    - Preface, undated (Box 295, Folder 14)
    - pp. 1-11, undated (Box 295, Folder 15)
    - pp. 12-34, undated (Box 295, Folder 16)
    - pp. 35-60, undated (Box 296, Folder 1)
    - pp. 61-76, undated (Box 296, Folder 2)
    - pp. 77-108, undated (Box 296, Folder 3)
    - pp. 109-128, undated (Box 296, Folder 4)
    - pp. 129-178, undated (Box 296, Folder 5)
    - pp. 179-244, notes, undated (Box 296, Folder 6)
  - Editorials, 1876-1919 (Box 296, Folder 7)
  - "The Higher Education of Women...", 1888 (Box 296, Folder 8)
  - "Influence of Sororities", 1907 (Box 296, Folder 9)
  - Joint Board of Examiners, undated (Box 296, Folder 10)
  - "The Natural Resources of India...", 1857 (Box 296, Folder 11)
  - "The Need of a Collegiate Education...", 1874 (Box 296, Folder 12)
  - "One Individual Often Represented...", 1858 (Box 296, Folder 13)
  - "Our Celtic Inheritance", 1870 (Box 296, Folder 14)
  - Praises and Prayer, 1892 (Box 296, Folder 15)
  - Prayers of a College Year, 1925 (Box 296, Folder 16)
  - Taylor, James M. (Memorial Tribute), 1917 (Box 296, Folder 17)
  - "Twenty-five Years of Woman's...", 1900 (Box 296, Folder 18)
  - "What the College Woman Can Do", 1910 (Box 296, Folder 19)
- SERIES V. PHOTOGRAPHS, 1857-1962; 4.04 linear feet
  Most of the Photographs in this series are of Seelye himself. These are arranged chronologically. Other photographs are arranged alphabetically, and include photographs of Seelye's cow, the Old North Church, publication photographs, Round Hill (the President's House), and Mrs. Henrietta Chapin Seelye. The portraits are arranged chronologically. This subseries includes depictions of Seelye in his public and private life. Photographs of Seelye's family are located in the folder identified as Henrietta Chapin Seelye's photographs.
  - 1857-1865 (Box 297, Folder 1)
  - (with Eugene Douglass), 1860 (Box 297.1)
  - Photographs (1857-1909), 1867 (Box 297, Folder 2)
  - 1872-1874 (Box 297, Folder 3)
  - 1875 (Box 297, Folder 4)
  - 1878-1879 (Box 297, Folder 5)
  - 1882-1884 (Box 297, Folder 6)
  - 1885-1887 (Box 297, Folder 7)
  - 1889 (Box 297, Folder 8)
  - 1891 (Box 297, Folder 9)
  - 1893 (Box 297, Folder 10)
  - 1894 (Box 297, Folder 11)
  - 1895-1898, 1900 (Box 297, Folder 19)
  - 1904 (Box 297, Folder 20)
  - 1905-06, 1909 (Box 297, Folder 21)
  - Photographs 1910 (Box 298, Folder 1)
  - 1910-1911 (Box 298, Folder 2)
  - 1911 (Box 298, Folder 3)
  - 1912-1917 (Box 298, Folder 4)
  - 1920-1924 (Box 298, Folder 5)
  - Cow, 1893 (Box 298, Folder 6)
  - Old North Church, Springfield, undated (Box 298, Folder 7)
  - Photographs used in publications, 1872-1923 (Box 298, Folder 8)
  - Round Hill, 1913-1914 (Box 298, Folder 9)
  - Mrs. Henrietta Chapin Seelye, 1888-1923; undated (Box 298, Folder 10)
  - Portraits
    - Correspondence, 1925; 1962; undated (Box 299, Folder 1)
    - Silhouettes and sketches, 1893-1895 (Box 299, Folder 2)
    - Silhouette, 1895 (Box 299.1)
    - Burleigh (?), 1872 (Box 299, Folder 3)
    - Weir, 1884-1886 (Box 299, Folder 4)
    - Tarbell, 1907-1908 (Box 299, Folder 5)
    - Hubbell, 1911 (Box 299, Folder 6)
    - Wright, Alice Morgan '04, 1914 (Box 299, Folder 7)
    - Etching: Elisabeth Telling '04, 1910 or 1920 (Box 299, Folder 8)
    - Bust: H.S. Manning, 1946 (Box 299, Folder 9)
- SERIES VI. HENRIETTA CHAPIN SEELYE, 1820-1925; 1.04 linear feet
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject, and when necessary, by date. The subseries are Correspondence, Family, and Journals. The correspondents are mostly family members. The Family papers cover both business and family matters. The Journals cover the years from 1859 - 1913 and are an excellent source for understanding Smith College during the years of Seelye's presidency. Other materials include photographs, manuscripts, publications, and a scrapbook.
  - Commercial Commission to U.S., 1913 (Box 300, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Family)
    - Eliza Chapin Blake to mother (Mrs. Sheldon Chapin), 1854 (Box 300, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. M. K. Moody, 1854; undated (Box 300, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Phelps, 1852 (Box 300, Folder 4)
    - To Mrs. Henrietta Chapin Seelye, 1854; undated (Box 300, Folder 5)
    - W.A. Sheldon to Adam Waldie, 1833 (Box 300, Folder 6)
  - Family
    - Lyman Chapin, 1820-1839 (Box 300, Folder 7)
    - Harriet Chapin, 1840-1854 (Box 300, Folder 8)
    - Harriet Chapin: journal, 1853 (Box 300, Folder 9)
    - Sheldon coat of arms, undated (Box 300, Folder 10)
  - Journals
    - 1859, 1862 (Box 300, Folder 11)
    - 1881-1884 (Box 300, Folder 12)
    - 1885-1887 (Box 300, Folder 13)
    - 1891, 1892 (Box 300, Folder 14)
    - 1893-1895 (Box 300, Folder 15)
    - 1896, 1897 (Box 300, Folder 16)
    - 1898, 1899 (Box 300, Folder 17)
    - Travels, 1900-1901 (Box 301, Folder 1)
    - 1900-1904 (Box 301, Folder 2)
    - 1905-1909 (Box 301, Folder 3)
    - 1910-1913 (Box 301, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript, 1890 (Box 301, Folder 5)
    - miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 301, Folder 6)
    - Obituary, 1925 (Box 301, Folder 7)
    - Publications, 1904 (Box 301, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook, 1857-1859 (Box 302, Folder 1)